Guide to the Simplified spelling collection, 1916-1920
Department of Special Collections
Simplified spelling collection,
1916-1920
Special Collections M0178
.25 linear ft.
Stanford University. Libraries. Dept. of Special Collections and University Archives.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
None.
Provenance
Source unknown.
Scope and Content
This collection contains papers from the movement for simplfied spelling in the A.I.M.E. (American Institute of Mining Engineers) lead by W. H. Shockley. Included are letters to and from Shockley, to and from other members of the A.I.M.E. type script arguments for simplified spelling circulated by Shockley, lists of names of members of the A.I.M.E., and numercus misc. memoranda concerning the campaign.
Container List
- 1. 13 Mar 1916-to William H. Shockley from H. G. Paine-Notice of election to membership (Box 1, Folder 1)
- 2. 26 Dec '18-Proposed circular-from Shockley
- 3. 3 Apr '19-from Bradley Stoughton, (2 copies)
- 4. 11 Apr '19-from Bradley Stoughton, (2 copies)
- 5. 19 Apr '19-from Bradley Stoughton, (2 copies)
- 6. 25 May '19-to Bradley Stoughton, (2 copies)
- 7. 30 May '19-memo from Shockley
- 8. 1 Jun '19-memo from W. H. S. to [?]
- 9. 1 Jan '19-proposed circular from Shockley
- 10. 13 Jan '18-memo from W. H. S to [?] requests letter ballot, (2 copies)
- 11. 29 Sept '19-memo from W. H. S, (5 copies)
- 12. 10 June '20-from H. G. Paine
- 13. 4 Nov '21-from E. L. Oliver
- 14. 15 Nov '21-to Oliver
- 15. 21 Nov '21-memo from W. H. S.
- 16. 6 Dec '21-memo from F. W. Bradley
- 17. 16 Dec '21-from W. H. S., (3 copies)
- 18. 16 Dec '21-to F. W. Bradley
- 1. 11 Oct '19-Revised draft of argument sent to Inst. of Mining & Metal Engineers (Box 1, Folder 2)
- 2. 20 Oct '19-Argument in favor of reformed spelling, (2 copies, no. 516)
- 3. 20 Oct '19-Revised draft of argument sent to Inst. of Mining & Metal Engineers W. H. S copy
- 4. 20 Oct '19-Revised draft of argument
- 5. 20 Oct '19-Revised draft of argument
- 6. 22 Sept '19-First draft of argument-signed by W. H. Carruth
- 7. 22 Sept '19-First draft of argument-signed by Hempl
- 8. 22 Sept '19-First draft of argument (no page 8)
- 9. 22 Sept '19-First draft of argument (no signature)
- 10. [?] Jan '20-Revised draft of argument (no signature)
- 11. [?] Jan '20-Revised draft of argument-signed by Chas. S. Burt
- 1. Names of persons signing proposal without comment (one of 3 pages missing) (Box 1, Folder 3)
- 2. Names of 1917signers who did not sign in 1919, (3 pages)
- 3. Signers of proposals according to Stoughtons list, (2 copies, 3 pages each)
- 4. Objectors to taking a vote and protestors by letter.
- 5. yes ballots
- 6. no ballots and letters
- 7. split ballots
- 8. list of those who signed petition for simplified spelling
- 9. List of names-List A
- 10. List of names-List B
- 11. Names and addresses of signers- June 15, 1919
- Signed circulars-concerning simplfied spelling (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - 1. T. L. Rausome
  - 2. H. D. McCaskey
  - 3. Edwin T. Blake
  - 4. F. N. Bradley
  - 5. S. C. Brethorton
  - 6. Albert Burch
  - 7. Ernest F. Buckland
  - 8. Chars. S. Burt
  - 9. Richard V. Hice
  - 10. H. M Howie
  - 11. Roswell H. Johnson
  - 12. C. E. Lawrence
  - 13. Horace [P?]
  - 14. D. B. Reger
  - 15. W. S. Rice
  - 16. Alfred Stansfield
  - 17. O. Smith
  - 18. C. F. Tohmas
  - 19. A. T. C. McChiaster
  - 20. Hydel[?]
  - 21. 2 unsigned
- 1. Petition for Simplified spelling- 1 Jan 1917A.I.M.E. (Box 1, Folder 5)
- 2. Petition for simplified spelling- 1 Jan 1917A.I.M.E.
- 3. Memo to members of A.I.M.E. about spelling- 27 June 1919
- 4. Memo to members of A.I.M.E. about spelling- 25 June 1919
- 5. Memo to President of A.I.M.E. plus notice to members- 1 Feb '19
- 6. Memo to members of A.I.M.E. (no date)
- 7. Reformed spelling inthe A.I.M.E.
- 8. A request to help inthereform of English spelling sent 12 Aug '18, (Shockley's copy)
- 9. Fragment: Page 2 of some list of corrections
- 10. Voting results-with Shockley's comments
- 11. Memorandum of Votes for Simplified Spelling
- 12. Certificate of incorporation for A.I.M.E.